<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Cienfuegos | Liliana Kastilio]]></title>
  <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/blog/categories/cienfuegos/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-01-30T21:24:40+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://lili2311.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Liliana Kastilio]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rancho Luna, Cuba]]></title>
    <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/11/19/Rancho-Luna/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/11/19/Rancho-Luna</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-19-Rancho-Luna/RanchoLuna01.jpg" title="Rancho Luna" alt="Rancho Luna Image" /></p>

<p>This is the nicest beach we have been to in Cuba so far. It has sand, fishes, coral reefs and a few bars and cafes.
I would not count on using the bathroom unless you are willing to go to every place and ask if you could pay to use their bathroom. Once you get there the coral reefs are to your left (if facing the water) around the curve towards the hotel (which can only be seen once you turn the corner). You should see people snorkeling there and it is quite shallow where the reef is. If you don&rsquo;t find it there are still fishes in the water out and about.</p>

<h4>Getting There</h4>

<p>You can get there by either taxi or local bus. There are also organised tours.
We took the bus every time, it was an interesting experience in itself. The buses go from the main Cienfuegos Bus Station:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-19-Rancho-Luna/RanchoLuna02.jpg" title="Bus Terminal" alt="El PradoImage" /></p>

<p>We took the 10am bus every time, the next one is 11:30. They are not very frequent! The local buses accept local currency (Moneda Nacional ie Peso). One way trip cost us $1 Peso (once it was $2 Peso because the driver demanded it). The space is limited on these buses and people with tickets board first and the rest of the pasengers squeeze on. Note that as a tourist you probably won&rsquo;t be able to acquire a ticket and will likely be redirected to the more expensive tourist bus. Simply follow the crowd and pay on board. Tube rush hour in London was nothing compared to this bus journey, it is hot, there is no space and the driver lets everyone on regardless of how much you are struggling to breathe. I had a rather large sweaty lady hugging me to keep stable with a very old man on the other side making pitiful noises every time someone leaned on him. Not the most comfortable bus ride but it is only about 20 minues or so throught the countryside. Get off once you see the sea and beach.</p>

<h4>Getting back</h4>

<p>Getting back is not very hard, exit the beach through the restaurants and car park. Once you reach the main road there is a rather large tree to your left. There are ussually people stadnign under it. This is the bus stop to get back, it is not sign posted in any way.</p>

<p>You can get back usign the local bus again or the private trucks. The trucks are a better but more expensive option, it is not as hot with much more available space and costs $10 Local Peso. The trucks are modified to become &ldquo;buses&rdquo; and come in all sorts of shapes and colours. There is ususally one around 15:30. Get the bus or the truck which every comes first, but the buses are less punctual than the trucks and the truck is actually a fun ride.</p>

<p>This is the view from the &ldquo;bus stop&rdquo;:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-19-Rancho-Luna/RanchoLuna03.jpg" title="Rancho Luna" alt="Rancho Luna Image" /></p>

<p>And here is our truck approaching:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-19-Rancho-Luna/RanchoLuna04.jpg" title="Rancho Luna" alt="Rancho Luna Image" /></p>

<p>I have been told that all buses and trucks from this stop go to Cienfuegos.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things to Do in Cienfuegos, Cuba]]></title>
    <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/11/18/Things-To-Do-In-Cienfuegos-Cuba/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/11/18/Things-To-Do-In-Cienfuegos-Cuba</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>Visit the Cienfuegos Pier</h4>

<p>You can spend some time on the pier which has some nice views of the bay and some fishing boats. On weekends at night they sometimes have music and dancing.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-18-Things-To-Do-In-Cienfuegos-Cuba/Cienfuegos01.jpg" title="Cienfuegos Pier" alt="Cienfuegos Pier Image" /></p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-18-Things-To-Do-In-Cienfuegos-Cuba/Cienfuegos02.jpg" title="Cienfuegos Pier" alt="Cienfuegos Pier Image" /></p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-18-Things-To-Do-In-Cienfuegos-Cuba/Cienfuegos03.jpg" title="Cienfuegos Pier" alt="Cienfuegos Pier Image" /></p>

<h4>Get a nice pork kebab by the pier</h4>

<p>Right by the pier you can relax in a cafe Muelle, which does awesome pork and pineapple kebabs and pina coladas.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-18-Things-To-Do-In-Cienfuegos-Cuba/Cienfuegos08.jpg" title="Muelle Cafe" alt="Kebab Image" /></p>

<h4>Spend an evening on the Malecon</h4>

<p>Most of the locals spend evenings here chatting with friends and there are a few bars/cafes across the road too.
You can simply stroll along the length of the Malecon or take a seat and watch the bay at night.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-18-Things-To-Do-In-Cienfuegos-Cuba/Cienfuegos04.jpg" title="Cienfuegos Malecon" alt="Cienfuegos Malecon Image" /></p>

<h4>Visit an 18th Century Cementary</h4>

<p>There are 2 gorgeous and very old cementaries in Cienfuegos, I only have pictures from one of them. The better one is much smaller and older with graves and statues dating back to 1800s you might get away with taking photos depending on what the caretaker agrees to. We had to pay a small fee to ba taken around ($10 local pesos). The caretaker was very knowlegeable about the history of different graves but only speaks Spanish.</p>

<p>The bigger cementary was a bit of a walk, I would recommend taking the bus if it is very hot. Bus number 3 stops there.
The entrance is free and you can walk around the different paths to see the older statues and gravestones. This cementary is more modern and it is in much better condition.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-18-Things-To-Do-In-Cienfuegos-Cuba/Cienfuegos05.jpg" title="Cienfuegos Cementario" alt="Cementario Image" /></p>

<h4>Walk along the El Prado</h4>

<p>This is the main street which leads towards the Malecon, in the evening there are lots of people simple walking around or sitting with friends on one of the many benches. The street is lined with cafes, restaurants and bars. If you want to spend less, buy drinks and food form the hole in the wall places for national currency.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-18-Things-To-Do-In-Cienfuegos-Cuba/Cienfuegos06.jpg" title="El Prado" alt="El PradoImage" /></p>

<h4>Go shopping on the Boulevrad</h4>

<p>There are a couple of small markets along here and some general grocery shops. There isn&rsquo;t much to buy really but interesting to see anyway.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-18-Things-To-Do-In-Cienfuegos-Cuba/Cienfuegos07.jpg" title="Market off the Boulevard" alt="Market off the Boulevard Image" /></p>

<h4>Day Trips</h4>

<p>You can take day trips to multiple places around Cienfuegos:</p>

<ol>
<li>El Nicho - small waterfall.</li>
<li>Rancho Luna - the nicest beach near here with fishes and coral reefs.</li>
<li>Cienfuegos Fort/Castle - just past Rancho Luna there is an old fort/castle.</li>
<li>Botanical Gardens.</li>
</ol>


<!-- ####Attractions
Some of thing Cienfuegos had to offer in terms of attractions are:

1. Rancho Luna - 
2. Cementary 1 (get names online)
3. Cementary 2 (get name online)
4. Park Marti Rosi?? (get name)
5. Malecon
6. Derelict Monastery
7. El Prado
8. Boulevard
9. Immigration Office Building
10. El Nicho -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cienfuegos, Cuba]]></title>
    <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/11/17/Cienfuegos-Cuba/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/11/17/Cienfuegos-Cuba</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-17-Cienfuegos-Cuba/Cienfuegos.jpg" title="Park Jose Marti" alt="Park Jose Marti Image" /></p>

<h4>Getting There</h4>

<p>We have kicked off our trip in a small city of Cienfuegos, Cuba. We landed in Varadero airport and from there Cienfuegos was a terryfying 2hr car trip. No seatbelts, no road signs and sparse road lights made every passing car seem like it was going to crash into us, but we arrived safely after all and this is simply something we would have to get used to (the buses turned out to be  a similar experience). We could have taken a bus from Varadero to Cienfuegos, but since in Cuba there is a separation of transport for tourists and locals it makes taking the bus together with my family difficult and due to only 3 or 4 buses a day we would&rsquo;ve had to spend the night in Varadero. The car seemed like a much better option.</p>

<h4>Family Visa</h4>

<p>I have lots of family in Cuba and we were staying with them on a Family Visa which was an adventure in itself to aquire on our first day here. While we entered the country on a Tourist Card, in order for us to stay in my family home we would have to change it to the Family Visa within 24hrs of arrival. Of course we could have done this back in London, but it seemed easier to do in Cuba (it was not). Not only did we have to sit in a scorching heat in the queue for ages, but to get everythign sorted required multiple trips to various places: bank, insurance office of some sort and the foreign exchange. After the lady giving out the visas had a long chat about what to do with us with her manager, apparently since I am a daughter of a Cuban citizen but do not have a cuban passport it was making things more complicated. In the end after some strange and personal questions, they agreed to give us the family visa an everything seemed to go well. That was until they demanded to see a printed copy of our travel insurance and since it is 26 pages long we obviously did not print it and bring it with us but instead had all the electonic copies on our phones. This did not go down well and we had to go to insurance office of some sort where they would &ldquo;verify&rdquo; our policy or simply make us buy a new one, which was actually more expensive for 2 weeks in Cuba than the entire 6 months backpacking insurance policy we already had! Luckily my dad talked to them in Spanish and we managed to convince them that electronic confirmations are the standard in UK and we were off to submit our travel insurance &ldquo;verification&rdquo; and collect a receipt in the bank to prove we have paid for the visa. After a full day of running around we had our visa. Success!</p>

<h4>Accomodation</h4>

<p>Our accomodation for the two weeks is my brothers house, which is currently in a complete renovation stage. We had the most &ldquo;finished&rdquo; room, but no running water. You don&rsquo;t appreciate running water until you don&rsquo;t have any! Simple things like brushing your teeth suddenly become difficult. Nothing could be accomplished without getting water first and storing it in buckets in our room. Separate drinking water had to be aquired as well, due to an outbreak of Cholera around Cuba. We managed to adapt quickly enough and now having a shower in the morning can be accomplished in the same amount of time as having a fully working bathroom. Thanks to water reservour under our room, a water pump, an industrial water heating element and multiple buckets we can have hot water within 5 minutes (unless the pump stops working!).</p>

<p>On a Tourist Card we could have stayed in a Casa Particular, which is most of the travellers here seem to do. This is basically a B&amp;B but they would have to register you as staying with them to the goverment. Running water, sometimes even hot water 24/7. Usually the hosts offer breakfasts an even dinners if requested (would very much recommend this option, especially after trying very hard to find somewhere to eat but more on that later).</p>

<h4>Photos</h4>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-17-Cienfuegos-Cuba/Cienfuegos01.jpg" title="Aduana Immigration Building" alt="Aduana Immigration Building Image" />
<img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-17-Cienfuegos-Cuba/Cienfuegos02.jpg" title="Cienfuegos Market" alt="Cienfuegos Market Image" />
<img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-17-Cienfuegos-Cuba/Cienfuegos03.jpg" title="Cienfuegos Pier Image" alt="Cienfuegos Melecon Image" />
<img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-17-Cienfuegos-Cuba/Cienfuegos04.jpg" title="Cienfuegos White Bus" alt="Cienfuegos White Bus" /></p>

<!-- INSERT HOUSE PICS AND MAYBE SOME CIENFUEGOS PICS TOO. -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
