<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Havana | Liliana Kastilio]]></title>
  <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/blog/categories/havana/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-04-17T21:47:44+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://lili2311.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Liliana Kastilio]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Food in Havana]]></title>
    <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/12/09/Food-in-Havana/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/12/09/Food-in-Havana</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On our arrival we quickly realised that we were luckily not staying in the tourist area and that meant all the food near us would be in local Peso and super cheap! We had a chance to try a whole lot of pizza from little hole-in-the-wall places and decided on our favourite spots to have pizza in Havana.</p>

<p>There are 2 that stand out the most: a little blue window on San Lazaro just past Aramburu street and a small place on the Boulevard (not the one in Old Havana, but the one behind the Capitolio) it is right next to some benches and a sandwich place which seems to share the same kitchen, this one is the only one we have seen to make full sized pizzas and to actually fully utilise all available ingredients in Cuba to make tasty pizzas rather than a 2 ingredient pizza available almost everywhere else. Unfortunately I don&rsquo;t have a picture of either of the places as I was too busy enjoying the food. But this is what the small pizzas look like:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-12-09-Food-in-Havana/Pizza.jpg" title="Pizza Jabon y Queso" alt="Pizza Jabon y Queso Image" /></p>

<p>Apart from pizza, there have been a few good meals. Mostly in small local places where the main dish is usually Chuleta or Lomo with rice (usually it is a smoked pork cutlet), sometimes there is also pasta, but ususally it is just that - pasta with not much else.</p>

<p>One evening we walked past what looked like a little pub/bar called El Pachanguero and luckily decided to try it out. The food was not bad compared to most other places and prices reasonable (they accepted CUC and Pesos). There are not many places with &ldquo;good&rdquo; food in Cuba to be honest.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-12-09-Food-in-Havana/ElPachanguero.jpg" title="El Pachanguero" alt="El Pachanguero Image" /></p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-12-09-Food-in-Havana/ElPachangueroInside01.jpg" title="El Pachanguero" alt="El Pachanguero Image" /></p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-12-09-Food-in-Havana/ElPachangueroInside02.jpg" title="El Pachanguero" alt="El Pachanguero Image" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Havana, Cuba]]></title>
    <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/12/07/Havana-Cuba/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/12/07/Havana-Cuba</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Havana is a beautiful city, well worth seeing. It is however very easy to leave with a wrong impression about Havana, on one side you have Old Havana which is extremely well kept and touristy and beautiful but you also have the side of Havana that the locals live in which is much bigger and well worth seeing.</p>

<p>On our journey to Trinidad we found out that there is a China Town in Havana, so on our second day we set out to find it. This is definitely the most disappointing China Town I have ever been to, but at least it had an arch:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/China-Town-Havana.jpg" title="China Town, Havana" alt="China Town Havana Image" /></p>

<p>Some of the buildings had the original Chinese signs and design, but very few and we only found about 3 places that even do chinese food. Given all that we skipped getting chinese and headed off towards the Capitolio in search of beans and rice.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Capitol-Havana.jpg" title="Capitol, Havana" alt="Capitolio Havana Image" /></p>

<p>Capitolio is a must see, it is grand and this is where you can find all the old cars parked and ready to give you a ride or a tour of the city. If you don&rsquo;t fancy that you can simply enjoy the view in the nearby park, by the Jose Marti Monument:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Jose-Marti-Monument-Havana.jpg" title="Jose Marti Monument, Havana" alt="Jose Marti Monument Havana Image" /></p>

<p>This is a nice place to relax in the evening before heading into Old Havana:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Old-Havana.jpg" title="Old Havana, Havana" alt="Old Havana Image" /></p>

<p>We spent a few evenings walking around Old Havana, it is full of beautiful old buildings but it is also full of tourists and people trying to sell you stuff.</p>

<p>Our daily walk back from all the sightseeing took us through the Malecon, this is a nice walk in the sunshine but beware of the waves soaking you on windy days. The view of the city is incredible and if you have time it stretches for hours and takes you through a couple of interesting monuments:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Malecon-Havana-01.jpg" title="Malecon, Havana" alt="Malecon Havana Image" /></p>

<p>And some quirky newer buildings:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Havana-Colourful-Building.jpg" title="Colouful Building, Havana" alt="Colourful Building Image" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Abandoned Havana, Cuba]]></title>
    <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/12/05/Abandoned-Havana-Cuba/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/12/05/Abandoned-Havana-Cuba</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There is a huge amount of abandoned buildings in Havana, everywhere you look you can find remains of something that used to be impressive and gorgeous. I think they are still beautiful in their own haunting way. This is a side of Havana that is easy to miss if you stick to touristy places and take a taxi everywhere.</p>

<p>We found this one while walking through the little residential streets in Old Havana. This is the most looked after part of the city but the residentials streets have not seen any TLC for a some time.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Abandoned-Havana-01.jpg" title="Abandoned Building, Havana" alt="Abandoned Building, Havana Image" /></p>

<p>This one is a huge construction site at the beginning of the El Prado, but looks like any work has been abandoned long ago.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Abandoned-Havana-02.jpg" title="Abandoned Building, Havana" alt="Abandoned Building, Havana Image" /></p>

<p>Not far is this ovegrown house just before one of the squares in Old Havana.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Abandoned-Havana-03.jpg" title="Abandoned Building, Havana" alt="Abandoned Building, Havana Image" /></p>

<p>We found this gorgeous mansion while exploring the Bodega area of Havana. It looks liek it has been a school at some point.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Abandoned-Havana-04.jpg" title="Abandoned Building, Havana" alt="Abandoned Building, Havana Image" /></p>

<p>And my favourite of them all is the glorious huge tree growing out of the building near the Hemingway&rsquo;s Daiquiry place in Old Havana.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Abandoned-Havana.jpg" title="Tree, Havana" alt="Tree growing on top of a building Image" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rancho Luna, Cuba]]></title>
    <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/11/19/Rancho-Luna/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/11/19/Rancho-Luna</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-19-Rancho-Luna/RanchoLuna01.jpg" title="Rancho Luna" alt="Rancho Luna Image" /></p>

<p>This is the nicest beach we have been to in Cuba so far. It has sand, fishes, coral reefs and a few bars and cafes.
I would not count on using the bathroom unless you are willing to go to every place and ask if you could pay to use their bathroom. Once you get there the coral reefs are to your left (if facing the water) around the curve towards the hotel (which can only be seen once you turn the corner). You should see people snorkeling there and it is quite shallow where the reef is. If you don&rsquo;t find it there are still fishes in the water out and about.</p>

<h4>Getting There</h4>

<p>You can get there by either taxi or local bus. There are also organised tours.
We took the bus every time, it was an interesting experience in itself. The buses go from the main Cienfuegos Bus Station:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-19-Rancho-Luna/RanchoLuna02.jpg" title="Bus Terminal" alt="El PradoImage" /></p>

<p>We took the 10am bus every time, the next one is 11:30. They are not very frequent! The local buses accept local currency (Moneda Nacional ie Peso). One way trip cost us $1 Peso (once it was $2 Peso because the driver demanded it). The space is limited on these buses and people with tickets board first and the rest of the pasengers squeeze on. Note that as a tourist you probably won&rsquo;t be able to acquire a ticket and will likely be redirected to the more expensive tourist bus. Simply follow the crowd and pay on board. Tube rush hour in London was nothing compared to this bus journey, it is hot, there is no space and the driver lets everyone on regardless of how much you are struggling to breathe. I had a rather large sweaty lady hugging me to keep stable with a very old man on the other side making pitiful noises every time someone leaned on him. Not the most comfortable bus ride but it is only about 20 minues or so throught the countryside. Get off once you see the sea and beach.</p>

<h4>Getting back</h4>

<p>Getting back is not very hard, exit the beach through the restaurants and car park. Once you reach the main road there is a rather large tree to your left. There are ussually people stadnign under it. This is the bus stop to get back, it is not sign posted in any way.</p>

<p>You can get back usign the local bus again or the private trucks. The trucks are a better but more expensive option, it is not as hot with much more available space and costs $10 Local Peso. The trucks are modified to become &ldquo;buses&rdquo; and come in all sorts of shapes and colours. There is ususally one around 15:30. Get the bus or the truck which every comes first, but the buses are less punctual than the trucks and the truck is actually a fun ride.</p>

<p>This is the view from the &ldquo;bus stop&rdquo;:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-19-Rancho-Luna/RanchoLuna03.jpg" title="Rancho Luna" alt="Rancho Luna Image" /></p>

<p>And here is our truck approaching:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-19-Rancho-Luna/RanchoLuna04.jpg" title="Rancho Luna" alt="Rancho Luna Image" /></p>

<p>I have been told that all buses and trucks from this stop go to Cienfuegos.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
