<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Cuba | Liliana Kastilio]]></title>
  <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/blog/categories/cuba/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-17T20:15:17+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://lili2311.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Liliana Kastilio]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Food in Havana]]></title>
    <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/12/09/Food-in-Havana/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/12/09/Food-in-Havana</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On our arrival we quickly realised that we were luckily not staying in the tourist area and that meant all the food near us would be in local Peso and super cheap! We had a chance to try a whole lot of pizza from little hole-in-the-wall places and decided on our favourite spots to have pizza in Havana.</p>

<p>There are 2 that stand out the most: a little blue window on San Lazaro just past Aramburu street and a small place on the Boulevard (not the one in Old Havana, but the one behind the Capitolio) it is right next to some benches and a sandwich place which seems to share the same kitchen, this one is the only one we have seen to make full sized pizzas and to actually fully utilise all available ingredients in Cuba to make tasty pizzas rather than a 2 ingredient pizza available almost everywhere else. Unfortunately I don&rsquo;t have a picture of either of the places as I was too busy enjoying the food. But this is what the small pizzas look like:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-12-09-Food-in-Havana/Pizza.jpg" title="Pizza Jabon y Queso" alt="Pizza Jabon y Queso Image" /></p>

<p>Apart from pizza, there have been a few good meals. Mostly in small local places where the main dish is usually Chuleta or Lomo with rice (usually it is a smoked pork cutlet), sometimes there is also pasta, but ususally it is just that - pasta with not much else.</p>

<p>One evening we walked past what looked like a little pub/bar called El Pachanguero and luckily decided to try it out. The food was not bad compared to most other places and prices reasonable (they accepted CUC and Pesos). There are not many places with &ldquo;good&rdquo; food in Cuba to be honest.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-12-09-Food-in-Havana/ElPachanguero.jpg" title="El Pachanguero" alt="El Pachanguero Image" /></p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-12-09-Food-in-Havana/ElPachangueroInside01.jpg" title="El Pachanguero" alt="El Pachanguero Image" /></p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-12-09-Food-in-Havana/ElPachangueroInside02.jpg" title="El Pachanguero" alt="El Pachanguero Image" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Havana, Cuba]]></title>
    <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/12/07/Havana-Cuba/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/12/07/Havana-Cuba</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Havana is a beautiful city, well worth seeing. It is however very easy to leave with a wrong impression about Havana, on one side you have Old Havana which is extremely well kept and touristy and beautiful but you also have the side of Havana that the locals live in which is much bigger and well worth seeing.</p>

<p>On our journey to Trinidad we found out that there is a China Town in Havana, so on our second day we set out to find it. This is definitely the most disappointing China Town I have ever been to, but at least it had an arch:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/China-Town-Havana.jpg" title="China Town, Havana" alt="China Town Havana Image" /></p>

<p>Some of the buildings had the original Chinese signs and design, but very few and we only found about 3 places that even do chinese food. Given all that we skipped getting chinese and headed off towards the Capitolio in search of beans and rice.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Capitol-Havana.jpg" title="Capitol, Havana" alt="Capitolio Havana Image" /></p>

<p>Capitolio is a must see, it is grand and this is where you can find all the old cars parked and ready to give you a ride or a tour of the city. If you don&rsquo;t fancy that you can simply enjoy the view in the nearby park, by the Jose Marti Monument:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Jose-Marti-Monument-Havana.jpg" title="Jose Marti Monument, Havana" alt="Jose Marti Monument Havana Image" /></p>

<p>This is a nice place to relax in the evening before heading into Old Havana:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Old-Havana.jpg" title="Old Havana, Havana" alt="Old Havana Image" /></p>

<p>We spent a few evenings walking around Old Havana, it is full of beautiful old buildings but it is also full of tourists and people trying to sell you stuff.</p>

<p>Our daily walk back from all the sightseeing took us through the Malecon, this is a nice walk in the sunshine but beware of the waves soaking you on windy days. The view of the city is incredible and if you have time it stretches for hours and takes you through a couple of interesting monuments:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Malecon-Havana-01.jpg" title="Malecon, Havana" alt="Malecon Havana Image" /></p>

<p>And some quirky newer buildings:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Havana-Colourful-Building.jpg" title="Colouful Building, Havana" alt="Colourful Building Image" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Abandoned Havana, Cuba]]></title>
    <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/12/05/Abandoned-Havana-Cuba/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/12/05/Abandoned-Havana-Cuba</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There is a huge amount of abandoned buildings in Havana, everywhere you look you can find remains of something that used to be impressive and gorgeous. I think they are still beautiful in their own haunting way. This is a side of Havana that is easy to miss if you stick to touristy places and take a taxi everywhere.</p>

<p>We found this one while walking through the little residential streets in Old Havana. This is the most looked after part of the city but the residentials streets have not seen any TLC for a some time.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Abandoned-Havana-01.jpg" title="Abandoned Building, Havana" alt="Abandoned Building, Havana Image" /></p>

<p>This one is a huge construction site at the beginning of the El Prado, but looks like any work has been abandoned long ago.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Abandoned-Havana-02.jpg" title="Abandoned Building, Havana" alt="Abandoned Building, Havana Image" /></p>

<p>Not far is this ovegrown house just before one of the squares in Old Havana.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Abandoned-Havana-03.jpg" title="Abandoned Building, Havana" alt="Abandoned Building, Havana Image" /></p>

<p>We found this gorgeous mansion while exploring the Bodega area of Havana. It looks liek it has been a school at some point.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Abandoned-Havana-04.jpg" title="Abandoned Building, Havana" alt="Abandoned Building, Havana Image" /></p>

<p>And my favourite of them all is the glorious huge tree growing out of the building near the Hemingway&rsquo;s Daiquiry place in Old Havana.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Abandoned-Havana.jpg" title="Tree, Havana" alt="Tree growing on top of a building Image" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cuban Food]]></title>
    <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/12/03/Cuban-Food/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/12/03/Cuban-Food</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While I can easily say I am a fan of Cuban food, I can imagine I would  have had a different opinion had I not been eating with my family. Typical meals would include rice and peas, fried plantain and smoked pork steak with some sort of fruit drinks like guava juice or pina colada. Breakfast is usually an omlette sandwich or cheese and ham sandwich (they come in a burger type bun and are called bocaditos). Street food or hole in wall places and definately more popular here than the restaurants, and we unfortunately found out why. Our attempts to eat out have not been very successful, first of all there aren&rsquo;t many restaurants in Cienfuegos but the ones we did try were extremely overpriced for what they were and not tasty in the slightest. Most popular food to buy on the go seems to be Bocaditos (sometimes toasted) and Pizza with most common fillings being Jamon (ham) and Queso (cheese), sometimes pineapple made an appearance. Cubans like sweet drinks and one of the popular ones are:</p>

<ul>
<li>Guarapo (sugar cane drink which is very sweet and green in colour).</li>
<li>Pina Colada</li>
<li>Guava Juice</li>
<li>Pineapple Juice</li>
<li>Mango Juice</li>
<li>Coconut Milk</li>
<li>Malta (malt fizzy drink)</li>
<li>Garapina (fermented pineapple drink)</li>
</ul>


<p>The hole in the wall places were not only better but also much cheaper as they took Pesos (Moneda Nacional) rather than CUC (Convertable Peso, used for tourists and more expensive places $1 CUC is around $25 Peso). You can exchange CUC to Peso in the foreign exhange offices (called Cadeca). Local Peso was pretty useful for buses, snacks and any small locals cafes. To give you some idea of the prices:</p>

<ul>
<li>Pizza: $5 - $10 Peso</li>
<li>Bocadito: $5 - $10 Peso</li>
<li>Pork Kebab/Bochanero: $1 CUCq</li>
<li>Coffee: $1 Peso or 1 CUC depending where you go</li>
<li>Refresco: $10 Peso</li>
<li>Cocktails/Beer: 1 CUC - 2 CUC</li>
<li>Restaurant meal: 5 CUC - 10 CUC</li>
</ul>


<p>There only two places to recommend really:</p>

<ol>
<li>El Rapido (the Cuban version of a McDonalds) - can be found on the Malecon, the Boulevard and near the hospital.</li>
<li>Cafe by the Pier - great pork kebab and pina colada, also nice croquetes and an excellent view. Sometimes they have Cuban music/dancing on weekends.</li>
</ol>


<h4>Photos</h4>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/ElRapido.jpg" title="El Rapido" alt="El Rapido Image" /></p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Kebab.jpg" title="Pineapple and Pork Kebab with Pina Colada " alt="Pineapple and Pork Kebab and Pina Colada Image" /></p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Casa-Particular-Breakfast.jpg" title="Casa Particular Breakfast" alt="Casa Particular Breakfast Image" /></p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Cuban-Dinner-Fish.jpg" title="Cuban Dinner with Fried Fish" alt="Cuban Dinner with Fried Fish Image" /></p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/Pizza.jpg" title="Pizza Jabon y Queso" alt="Pizza Jabon y Queso Image" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giron, Cuba]]></title>
    <link href="http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/11/26/Giron-Cuba/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://lili2311.github.io/blog/2014/11/26/Giron-Cuba</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Giron is a beach and small town in the Bay of Pigs located on one of the worlds largest wetlands.</p>

<h4>Getting There</h4>

<p>We travelled there by car as the whole family wanted to come along to the amazing coral reefs but there are also some buses going to Havana (especially Viazul) stop in town and from there it is a short journey by taxi to all the attractions.</p>

<h4>Attractions</h4>

<h4>1. Playa Giron</h4>

<p>This is a small and gorgeous beach perfect for relaxing and bathing, it was not busy at all when we went and there is a small drinks shack one one end of the beach serving up cocktails and fresh coconuts.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-26-Giron-Cuba/PlayaGiron.jpg" title="Playa Giron" alt="Playa Giron Image" /></p>

<h4>2. Cueva de los Peces</h4>

<p>This is a 70m deep flooded cenote. It is full of brightly colourded tropical fish which can be seen while snorkeling or diving if you want to go deeper into the darker waters below. The sea water here mixes with fresh water giving it a sligtly unfamiliar feel.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-26-Giron-Cuba/GironLake.jpg" title="Giron Lake" alt="Giron Lake Image" /></p>

<h4>3. Coral Reefs</h4>

<p>Just outside the park with the Cueva de los Peces across the road is a small beach full of coral reefs. Perfect for snorkeling or even diving and you can take diving lessons here as well.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-26-Giron-Cuba/GironBeach.jpg" title="Giron Reef Beach" alt="Giron Reef Beach Image" /></p>

<h4>4. Bay of Pigs Museum</h4>

<p>Museo Playa Giron (Bay of Pigs Museum) in Cuba is dedicated to the Bay of Pigs invasion. The museum itself is small and houses a collection of photographs and other historic pieces relating to the invasion. It also has some military vehicles on display.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-26-Giron-Cuba/GironMuseum.jpg" title="Giron Museum" alt="Giron Museum Image" /></p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-26-Giron-Cuba/GironTank.jpg" title="Giron Tank" alt="Giron Tank Image" /></p>

<p>I could&rsquo;t resist brtinging the family dog along, his name is Marley (after Bob Marley). I think he enjoyed Giron too!</p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-26-Giron-Cuba/MarleyGiron01.jpg" title="Marley enjoying the beach" alt="Marley Image" /></p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-26-Giron-Cuba/MarleyGiron02.jpg" title="Marley enjoying the beach" alt="Marley Image" /></p>

<p><img src="http://www.lilianakastilio.co.uk/images/2014-11-26-Giron-Cuba/MarleyGiron03.jpg" title="Marley enjoying the beach" alt="Marley Image" /></p>

<p>Overall Giron is an excellent day trip, and is definitely unforgettable.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
